There are good and bad photo copies for the process we are going to go through today.
For a general guideline, contrast.
Lots of contrasts.
You are going to see that if you have lots of gray, that's sort of washed out, colors on your photo copy, they'll transfer, they'll be there, but they won't really show up that well.
What you want, you want contrast, you want the shapes to come out.
Take for example this photo copy.
I have a guy in a mask.
Why do I have this?
Well he makes a good example.
First off his neckline and jacket is very dark, this is going to show up.
These shoulder areas are going to be very pronounced in our transfer because it's nice and dark.
For the lighter areas that you do have, they are also really flanked by darks so the shapes are still going to be there.
It's ok to be light or you know to be close to white, that's fine.
But you have to have a defining darker shapes around your photo copy.
So you can see here like around the eyes, the hair, the shoulders, those are all going to show up really well, or going to help kind of fill in the rest of the face in your minds eye.
Now a lot of photo copy machines will have a contrast.
And where you can darken and lighten and use more or less toner for your photo copy.
In general if you are going to make like an average black and white photocopy, do at least one or two extra in terms of the darkness and see what you get.
Usually a photo copy that you think is going to be too extreme and too glaring, will be really perfect for our photo copy transfer.